CHIH-LUN TSAI (NICK)

Full Stack Developer

Toronto, ON | (647) 332-1026 | nicktsai1026@gmail.com | in LinkedIn

SUMMARY:

Solution-oriented and problem solver with 4 years of experience building and maintaining web applications. Proficient in TypeScript, Node.js, PostgreSQL, AWS, and frontend frameworks like Polymer.js and Next.js. I am also familiar with Agile methodologies, version control systems like Git, and cross-browser compatibility testing.

SKILLS:

- Languages: JavaScript, HTML, CSS, TypeScript, Java, Swift
- Frameworks: Node.js, Next.js, Express.js, Polymer.js, Ionic 2, Bootstrap, TailwindCSS
- Databases: PostgreSQL, MongoDB
- Tools: Git, AWS, Docker, JIRA, Postman, Cypress, Google Analytics

WORK EXPERIENCE:

10Life Group Limited, Hong Kong

Apr 2018 - Apr 2022

Software Engineer | Lead Engineer

- Focused on developing and revamping the website and mobile app using Polymer.js, including optimizing UI/UX and SEO performance.
- Involved in developing and maintaining the infrastructure and microservices on AWS, including Amazon Lambda, CloudFront, API Gateway, ECS, RDS, and Elastic Load Balancing.
- Collaborated closely with other developers and designers to deliver new features on time.
- Developed a RESTful API that provides our clients access to the top products anticipated for the upcoming quarter and generates an average of approximately 1000 weekly redirects to our website.
- Implemented GitLab CI/CD pipeline to automate comprehensive unit testing and streamline the deployment process, enabling efficient and seamless code integration and deployment to the AWS platform.

Entinux Ltd., Hong Kong

Oct 2017 - Apr 2018

Project Specialist

- Assisted project manager in managing the projects including filing issue reports, gathering information, and closely tracking developer progress.
- Collaborated with developers to create a real-time map mobile application and an admin console system using Ionic 2, Node.js, Express.js, Handlebars.js, and MongoDB.
- Independently developed a server alert application utilizing Ionic 2 that enables the technical team to receive real-time alerts regarding server issues, allowing them to resolve any problems before the clients become aware of them.

EDUCATION:

Ming Chuan University, Taiwan

Sep 2007 - Jun 2011

Bachelor of Information and Telecommunications Engineering

Accelerate Coding Bootcamp, Hong Kong

Jun 2017 - Sep 2017

Certificate of Full Stack Web Development